They say that history is written by the victors.
都说历史是胜利者书写的
This then, is the history of the Umbrella Corporation.
那么  这就是保护伞公司的历史
Formed by crusading scientist, Professor James Marcus.
由激进的科学家詹姆斯·马库斯成立
Marcus had a young daughter, Alicia,
马库斯有一个小女儿  艾丽西娅
afflicted with progeria,
得了早衰症
a progressive, fatal, wasting disease.
一种无法治愈  不断恶化的致命疾病
Progeria caused premature aging.
早衰症导致她过早地衰老
By the time she was 25,
到她25岁时
Alicia would have the body of a 90 year old.
艾丽西娅的身体却已经90岁了
Marcus was driven to save her.
马库斯一心想要救她
But the odds seemed impossible.
但机会渺茫
And even as he worked desperately to create a cure,
在他拼命研究治疗方法的同时
the young girl's father would record his daughter,
小女孩的父亲记录下了他的女儿
her voice, her likeness, saving her for posterity.
她的声音  样貌  为后世保存起来
But then a breakthrough came.
但接着研究就有了突破
Marcus discovered the T-Virus.
马库斯发现了T病毒
Once injected, it would
一经注射
detect and repair damaged cells within the body.
它就会发现并修复体内的受损细胞
It was a miracle.
简直是奇迹
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved.
艾丽西娅·马库斯得救了
The T-Virus had a myriad of applications,
T病毒的作用不可限量
treating a thousand different diseases.
能治愈上千种不同疾病
Overnight, it seemed a new era was dawning.
一夜之间  世界似乎进入了新纪元
A world without the fear of infection, sickness or decay.
一个不再畏惧感染  疾病和衰老的世界
But it was not to be.
但它并非如此
For the T-Virus had certain, unforeseen side effects.
T病毒还有未曾预见的副作用
Sir, sir, over here!
老师  这边
He's not breathing.
他没呼吸了
The first of the undead was born.
第一个僵尸诞生了
The incident was quickly covered up.
事故很快被掩盖
In the aftermath, James Marcus
之后  詹姆斯·马库斯
argued furiously with his business partner,
与他的商业伙伴激烈争辩
Dr. Alexander Isaacs.
亚历山大·艾萨克斯博士
I don't care how much it costs.
我不在乎代价有多大
We have to close the program down.
我们必须停止这个项目
James, we're gonna be ruined.
詹姆斯  那样我们就完了
My mind is made up.
我心意已决
Pity.
可惜了
Off to bed, Alicia.
回床上去  艾丽西娅
Your father and I are just talking.
你父亲和我只是在谈话而已
Go on.
去吧
Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner's child.
艾萨克斯博士监护起他死去的合伙人的孩子
And her half of the company.
于是属于她的半个公司也落入他手
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals,
公司开始滋生诸多傲慢的理想
had been seduced completely by greed, and power.
完全为贪婪与权力所引诱
To help him control the now
为了帮助他控制
vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation,
保护伞公司现在的巨大利益
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence.
艾萨克斯博士创造了一个强大的人工智能
Isaacs used the likeness
艾萨克斯用了
of Alicia Marcus
艾丽西娅·马库斯的样貌
for the computer's interface.
作为计算机的交互界面
Isaacs called the computer The Red Queen.
艾萨克斯把这台计算机叫做红后
Then, 10 years ago in Raccoon City,
接着  十年前  在浣熊市
there was an outbreak.
一场生化危机爆发
The T-virus escaped from
T病毒从一处
an underground laboratory called The Hive.
叫做蜂巢的地下实验室外泄
The American government attempted
美国政府试图
to contain the outbreak by detonating a bomb.
通过投放炸弹控制危机
It devastated Raccoon City.
这摧毁了浣熊市
But it couldn't stop the airborne infection.
但它没能阻止空气传播感染
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days.
病毒爆发在几天内传遍全球
Humankind was brought to its knees.
人类倒在病毒脚下
Finally, the last and best hope of humanity,
最终  人类最后也是最大的希望
gathered and took a last stand in Washington DC.
聚集在一起  在华盛顿特区背水一战
But we didn't realize that what we had walked into...
但我们并没有意识到我们步入的
was a trap. My name is Alice. And this is my story.
是个圈套  我叫爱丽丝  这是我的故事
The end... of my story.
我故事的结局
Hello?
有人吗
Is there anyone alive in here?
还有人活着吗
- You come here to gloat? - My satellites show
-来幸灾乐祸的吗  -我的卫星显示
there are 4,472 humans remaining on the surface of the Earth.
地球表面还有4472名人类存活着
They will cease to exist in under 48 hours.
他们将会在48小时内消失
What do you want from me?
你想要我怎样
Want me to say that you've won?
要我说你赢了吗
- You've wiped out humanity. - No. Quite the opposite.
-你灭绝了人类  -不  恰恰相反
I want you to stop me.
我要你阻止我
Behind you.
小心身后
- Nicely done. - I don't trust you.
-干得漂亮  -我不相信你
Given our history, I'd be surprised if you did.
鉴于我们的过往  你相信我才惊讶
But unless you intervene, the slaughter will be complete.
但除非你介入  否则我将完成屠杀
- There will be no survivors. - How can I possibly help them?
-地球再无一人幸存  -我怎么可能救得了
Umbrella developed an airborne antivirus.
保护伞研究出了一种空气传播的病毒抗体
If released, it would destroy the
释放抗体  那么一经接触
T-Virus and anything it has infected on contact.
它就会摧毁T病毒及其感染过的一切
- All this could end? - Precisely.
-这一切就可以结束了  -正是
Where is this antivirus?
病毒抗体在哪里
Beneath the streets of Raccoon City, in the Hive.
在浣熊市地下  蜂巢里
Why would you help me?
你为什么要帮我
My programming will not allow me to harm
我的程序不允许我
the Umbrella Corporation.
伤害保护伞公司
But you are bound by no such constraints.
但你不受此限制
You'd turn against Umbrella?
你要对抗保护伞
Against the people who created you? Why?
对抗创造了你的人  为什么
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours. Make it to the Hive.
在48小时内赶到浣熊市  进入蜂巢
And then you'll have your answer.
答案就在那里
I have no reason to believe a word you say.
我没有理由相信你说的任何话
True. But I can offer you something you want very much.
没错  但我能给你一样你很想要的东西
- What is that? - Revenge. Wesker.
-什么  -复仇  威斯克
He led you all here to Washington.
他一路将你引来华盛顿
He pretended to give you your powers back.
假装把你的能力还给了你
And then, he betrayed you.
接着  他背叛了你
Where is he?
他在哪
He just landed at the Hive. I'm resetting your watch.
他刚刚抵达蜂巢  我正在重置你的手表
The clock is ticking.
时间紧迫
Alice.
爱丽丝
Ten years ago in the Hive, we both failed.
十年前在蜂巢  我们都失败了
We let this happen.
是我们造成了这一切
Make it right.
这次纠正它
Is that all you got?
你就这点能耐
Alice.
爱丽丝
10 years ago in the Hive... There will be no survivors...
十年前在蜂巢...地球再无一人幸存...
What is this place?
这是哪
Where am I? Answer me!
我在哪  回答我
What's wrong with you? Who did this?
你们怎么了  这是谁干的
Be quiet. Quiet!
安静  安静
I told you...
我说了...
Silence.
安静
So you're awake at last.
你终于醒了
- I killed you. - Yet here I am.
-我明明杀了你  -然而我就在你眼前
A clone...
是克隆人
- I killed your clone. - You've been most troublesome to me.
-我杀了你的克隆  -你是我最大的麻烦
You and your sisters.
你和你的姐妹们
And now I have you.
现在我抓到你了
The cleansing operation should've finished over a year ago,
清除计划早该在一年前完成
but you slowed us down.
但你拖慢了我们的进度
So much so, that I was obliged to take command myself.
所以  我不得不亲自指挥
You could end all of this.
你可以结束这一切
Why don't you?
为何不呢
Interesting.
有意思
Someone told you something, didn't they?
有人跟你说了什么  不是吗
Oh, well, you'll be begging to tell me soon enough.
你很快就会求着告诉我的
She's an unbeliever.
她是无神者
What do we do with unbelievers?
我们怎么处理无神者
Cast her out!
驱逐她
Cast her out! Cast her out!
驱逐她  驱逐她
- Come on! - Cast her out!
-来吧  -驱逐她
Cast her out!
驱逐她
God created a flood to cleanse the Earth.
上帝创造了一场洪水来净化地球
40 days and 40 nights of rain.
40个日夜的大雨
Our method is taking a little longer,
我们的方法花的时间稍微长点
but the result will be the same.
但结果会是一样的
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit.
留下一个干净纯粹的世界
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours.
我们将在12小时后抵达浣熊市
I doubt even you can run for that long.
我怀疑即便是你也跑不了那么久
I want to know what you know.
我要知道你知道些什么
Tell me when she's ready to talk.
她愿意开口时告诉我
- Wesker. - Dr. Isaacs.
-威斯克  -艾萨克斯博士
Look what I found on the roadside.
看我在路边找到了什么
It would appear your mission to
看来你的华盛顿任务
Washington was less successful than you made out.
没有你说的那么成功
Impossible.
不可能
I hope you didn't leave any other loose ends.
希望你没有再留下别的祸根了
There's something else.
除此之外
I think she knows about the airborne antivirus.
我想她知道了空气传播病毒抗体的事
- How can that be? - I don't know. Yet.
-怎么可能  -我还不知道  暂时
But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City.
但我们是在去浣熊市的路上抓到的她
Why else would she be headed there?
她去那还能有什么原因
Raise the security level at the Hive to maximum.
把蜂巢的安保级别升至最高
No one in or out. I'll let you know when she talks.
任何人不得进出  她开口了我会告诉你
God go with you.
上帝与你同在
You heard him. Security level to maximum.
你听见他说的了  安保级别升至最高
As you wish.
如你所愿
Get up there and check it out.
上去看看
Release me!
给我解开
- Open them. - Alright.
-把它们解开  -好
Alright.
好
You can't use it. You can't escape!
你骑不了它  你逃不了
Fire at her!
向她开火
Jesus!
天哪
Sir.
长官
She's gone.
她逃跑了
Target is 72 miles and closing.
目标还有116公里  正在逼近
Lock down the Hive. Prepare defensive measures.
封锁蜂巢  准备防御措施
And alert our operative in Raccoon City.
通知浣熊市的特勤人员
Welcome home.
欢迎回家
Airborne antivirus...
空气传播抗体病毒
48 hours...
48小时
Make it to the Hive.
进入蜂巢
Let him go! Let him go now!
放开他  放开他
Put it down or we'll shoot!
快放下否则我们开枪了
I told you, Doc! I told you you were wrong!
我早说了的  医生  我早就说你错了
Calm down, Christian! Calm down!
冷静  克里斯汀  冷静
We should've killed her when we had the chance!
我们早该在有机会的时候杀了她
Put it down, please. Before he tries to shoot the both of us.
放下  拜托  在他还没射杀我俩之前
What's in this?
这里面是什么
- Pure adrenaline. I needed you awake. - Why?
-纯肾上腺素  我需要叫醒你  -为什么
There's something coming.
有东西要来了
In the same direction you came in. Something big.
在你进来的方向  大家伙
Let him go! Put it down, now!
放了他  快放下
Alice.
爱丽丝
Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia.
保护伞公司在阿卡迪亚抓住了我
We were headed somewhere called the Hive.
我们被押往一处叫蜂巢的地方
Got loose, killed the pilot. Crashed here.
挣脱捆绑  杀了飞行员  坠毁在这里
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash.
医生跟其他人把我从残骸中救了出来
- I owe them my life. - Doc!
-我欠他们一条命  -医生
There, to the east.
在那  东边
It's still headed our way.
仍然冲着我们这过来
You know what it is?
你知道那是什么吗
Umbrella. Doctor Isaacs.
保护伞公司  艾萨克斯博士
I thought that you killed him.
我以为你已经杀了他
I thought so, too.
我也以为
He has an army of undead with him. He'll be here within hours.
他有支僵尸军队  几小时内就会到这
- What do we do? - Why the hell are we asking her?
-我们怎么办  -我们为什么要问她
She's a stranger. We shouldn't have trust her...
她是个陌生人  我们不能信任她
Don't you touch me, Doc!
别碰我  医生
- Put it down! Christian! - You put it down!
-把枪放下  克里斯汀  -你把枪放下
Look at me. Just cause you
看着我  就因为
think you should be in charge, doesn't make it so.
你觉得自己应该当老大  并不代表你就是
You listen to me, Doc.
你给我听好了  医生
You're gonna regret it. All of you!
你会后悔的  你们都会
All of you!
你们都会后悔的
I have to get to the Hive.
我必须得去蜂巢
You have to get these people out of here.
你得带他们离开这里
We have children. Injured. The elderly.
我们这有孩子  伤员还有老人
Now what chance do they have on the open road?
跑出去他们哪还有生还的可能
Better than they have here.
概率总比待在这里的大
- This building is secure. - Maybe from the undead.
-这栋楼很安全  -或许是不怕僵尸
But Isaacs has armored vehicles.
但艾萨克斯有装甲车
Rocket launchers, heavy ordinance.
火箭发射器  还有重机枪
They're gonna tear this place wide open.
他们会把这里夷为平地的
Doc!
医生
So what happened to her?
她怎么了
She's set off one of the traps we had on perimeter.
她中了我们在防线上设置的一处陷阱
Not intended for the undead.
不是给僵尸准备的
- What is this? - Specialty of the house.
-这是什么  -当日特饮
Have you in your feet in no time.
能让你立马振作起来
Why should I trust you?
我为什么要相信你
Here.
给
Doc, you need to get out there.
医生  麻烦你出来一下
People are scared and Christian's not helping.
大家都很害怕  克里斯汀完全在帮倒忙
We need to let people know what's happening.
我们得让大家清楚状况
Okay.
好
I've got to go.
我得走了
Hey. Your friend's gonna be okay.
你朋友不会有事的
Thank you.
谢谢你
- You know, he and I... - I noticed.
-他和我...  -看出来了
So what's in the Hive?
蜂巢里有什么
Umbrella developed a cure.
保护伞公司研究出了解药
An airborne antivirus.
一种空气传播的抗体病毒
It'll destroy anything infected with the T-Virus on contact.
一经接触就能摧毁T病毒感染过的一切
- Who told you this? And you believed her? - The Red Queen.
-谁告诉你的  你竟然相信她  -红后
What if we could end all this?
如果我们能结束这一切呢
What about you? They infected you with the T-Virus.
那你呢  他们也给你注射了T病毒
You release this antivirus, it's going to kill you.
你要释放的这种病毒抗体也会杀死你
- Whatever it takes. - Alice, I'm not...
-我不在乎  -爱丽丝  我不...
You know I'm right.
你知道我是对的
All right.
好吧
We stop Isaacs here. We save these people,
我们先打败艾萨克斯  救下这些人
and then we go together.
然后我们一起去蜂巢
We don't have long.
我们时间不多了
Let's get to it.
开始行动吧
What else do you have for defense?
你们还有什么可供防御的武器
Not too many firearms, we have a big supply of gasoline.
没有太多枪支  但有充足的汽油
Here. You need a weapon.
给  你需要一把武器
We're giving her a gun now?
我们都给她枪了吗
Take it easy, Christian.
别激动  克里斯汀
You can let your guard down if you want, man. I don't intend to.
你尽可以降低警惕  但我不会
When I rode in here, someone was watching me.
我骑车到这的时候  有人在盯着我
They could've called out or fired
他本来可以大喊或开枪
a shot to warn me about the trap but they didn't.
来提醒我这里有陷阱  但他没有
- What are you saying? - Watch your back.
-什么意思  -当心背后有人捅刀子
So Dr. Isaacs, it seems you let her slip through your fingers.
艾萨克斯博士  看来你又让她逃脱了
A lot remains of them.
而且他们很多人都还活着
Don't forget who you're talking to. Where is she?
别忘了你在跟谁说话  她在哪
A settlement in Raccoon City.
浣熊市的一个据点
Our informant reports that she's preparing for a fight.
据线人汇报  她正在准备战斗
Good. I'll be there in the hour.
很好  我一个小时就到
That's it. Keep moving.
就是这样  继续推
We need all the gasoline cans. Over there.
我们需要所有的汽油桶  放那边
- Claire said you built this. - That's right.
-克莱尔说这是你建的  -没错
This used to be a window washer.
这本来是一台窗户清洗器
- I made a couple of changes. - Where did you learn to do that?
-我做了点改装  -你在哪儿学的
My father used to run a chop shop. I hated it.
我爸爸以前开了一家拆车厂  我讨厌它
Who knew? I guess I was paying attention after all.
谁知道呢  开来当时还是有在认真学吧
Good. Because I'm gonna need you
很好  我想让你
to make a few more changes to this thing.
把这东西再改装一下
Ready the weapons. High explosive rounds.
武器就位  装填高爆炸药
No survivors.
不留活口
He's here.
他来了
They're coming! Close the gates!
他们来了  关上大门
My God. It's an army.
天啊  这简直是支军队
What are we gonna do?
我们要怎么办
Yeah. What are we gonna do?
是啊  我们要怎么办
We're gonna kill every last one of them.
我们杀光他们
Prepare to fire!
准备开火
Get ready!
准备好
Light it up!
点火
Fire!
发射
Damn her!
操他妈的
Reload.
再次装填
Close it up. Full stop.
靠边  全面停止进攻
Release the bait.
放出诱饵
- There's a survivor. Open the gate. - Open the gate!
-有幸存者  打开大门  -打开大门
Open fire! Keep them off her.
开火  给她打掩护
Marker 2!
第二发就绪
Fire!
发射
Claire, Doc, get out there. Bring her in.
克莱尔  医生  出去把她带进来
Come on!
快点
Wait.
等等
She's almost there.
她快到了
Fire.
开火
Damn you. Close the gate now!
妈的  关上大门  快
Claire, they've breached the gate.
克莱尔  他们突破大门了
Claire!
克莱尔
Fire.
开火
Razor, now!
瑞瑟尔  现在
Right! You heard her. Push!
遵命  你们听到她说的了  推
Move!
快走
Abandon the gate. Pull back to the barricades.
放弃大门  撤回到路障
Looks like she's out of tricks. Target the roof.
看来她没新招了  瞄准屋顶
Everybody get down!
所有人趴下
Now!
快
Alice! We're at the barricades.
爱丽丝  我们到路障了
Claire, you have to hold them there.
克莱尔  你们必须挡住它们
Doc!
医生
Alice! We can't hold on much longer.
爱丽丝  我们撑不了多久了
Get out of there, now.
马上撤退
Back up. Now!
补给弹药  快
Bring all guns to bear.
对她集中所有火力
Fire.
开火
Where is she?
她在哪儿
Where have she gone?
她去哪儿了
Find her.
找到她
Close the vents! Now!
关闭通风口  快
Don't shoot!
别开枪
You're fast, but you're not too smart.
你动作很快  但你不够机智
- Don't shoot, please. - Where is he?
-别开枪  拜托  -他在哪儿
That way.
那边
Save your ammo.
省着点弹药
There's too many of these things still out here.
这玩意儿实在太多了
I'll take care of it.
我来解决
No.
别动
- Move out. - Let's go!
-出发  -走
Enjoy the ride.
享受旅程吧
Guys. There's something here you gotta see.
伙计们  你们过来看看
Go.
说
Two more armies of undead. Headed straight for us.
有两支丧尸军团朝我们过来了
There. On the horizon.
地平线这里一支
And a second over there.
还有这里一支
We're out of gasoline. We're defenseless.
我们没汽油了  已经无力防御
I have to make it to the Hive. It's our only chance now.
我们必须赶到蜂巢  这是唯一的机会
- I'll come with you. - Count me in.
-我和你一起去  -算我一个
Me, too.
我也是
And me.
还有我
I was wrong about you. Blow me.
我之前误会你了  倒霉
We know where you're going. Into the pit.
我们知道你们要去哪儿  进入深井
We want to come.
请让我们加入
Please.
拜托了
Grab some gear. You're gonna need it.
带上些装备  你们会用得着
There.
在那
What is it?
这是什么
The part of the Hive exposed by the blast.
爆炸后一部分暴露出来的蜂巢
That's our way in.
我们就从那儿进去
- Let's move! - I'll take point.
-行动  -我打头
Activate security measures now.
启动安全监测
Hive security fully activated and automated.
蜂巢安保系统已完全启动并进入自动操作
No.
不
Disengage automation. I'll handle the defenses myself.
退出自动操作  我亲自操作防御系统
Defenses will be more efficient if I retain control of them.
由我来控制防御系统会更有效率
Really? I seem to remember
是吗  我好像记得
last time she was here she walked out alive.
上次她从这儿活着出去了
I don't intend to make that same mistake.
我不想再犯同样的错误
As you wish. Hive defenses are now in your hands.
如你所愿  蜂巢防御系统现在由你掌控
Unleash the Cerberus.
放出地狱犬
Cerberus on play.
地狱犬上场
Did you have someone? Before all this?
你之前有亲人吗
Husband? Family?
丈夫  家庭什么的
- Can't remember. - How is that possible?
-我不记得了  -怎么可能
I woke up just when all of this was starting.
我醒来的时候这一切已经开始了
Can't recall much before that.
之前的事想不太起来
Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life.
有时候我觉得这就是我生活的全部
Running. Killing.
亡命天涯  杀戮不息
- What is it? - Something's stalking us.
-怎么了  -有东西跟着我们
- Are you sure? - This is what I do.
-你确定  -我就是干这行的
Run!
跑
Run, fast!
快跑
Come on!
快
Is everyone okay?
都还好吗
This way!
这边
Right behind us!
在我们后面
Why'd they stop?
它们怎么停下了
- Maybe they're scared. - Scared of what?
-也许它们是害怕了  -怕什么
Whatever's down there.
怕那下面的什么东西
Seal the Hive.
封闭蜂巢
Let's go!
走
Alice!
爱丽丝
- You okay? - Yeah.
-你没事吧  -没事
My mag's half empty.
我弹夹已经空了一半了
Lost my guns at the lake.
我把枪落在湖里了
I only got one round left.
我只剩枪膛里的子弹
One spare mag and then I'm out.
我还有一个备用弹夹
No guns, no ammo, what the hell are we gonna do down here?
没枪没弹药  我们下来干吗
Alice. What's with the lights?
爱丽丝  灯怎么灭了
There's a part of the Hive that's damaged.
蜂巢有一部分受损
- Power's erratic. - Here. Take this.
-电力不稳定  -拿上这个
Hey. Look.
你们看
You asked why I'd turn against Umbrella.
你之前问我为什么背叛保护伞公司
And I promised you an answer.
我承诺过会告诉你原因
Soon after the T-Virus was released,
在T病毒泄露后不久
a secret file was uploaded to my data stream.
一份机密文件上传到了我的数据流
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella High Command.
那是一份病毒爆发前17个月召开的
Dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occurred.
保护伞公司高层会议的记录
We're here today, not just
我们今天在这儿
to talk about the future of this company.
不仅要讨论公司的未来
We're here to talk about its destiny.
我们也要讨论它的使命
We're here to talk about the end of the world.
以及世界的终结
We stand on the brink of Armageddon.
我们就站在末日边缘
Diseases for which we have no cure.
我们承受着无法治愈的疾病
Fundamentalist states who call for our destruction.
原教旨主义自求毁灭
Nuclear powers over which we have no control.
面对核武器我们束手无策
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters,
即使我们渡过这一切的难关
we face other even more inevitable threats.
还是会面临其他更不可避免的威胁
Global warming will melt the polar ice caps within 80 years,
全球变暖将在80年内融化两极的冰盖
flooding 90 % of all habitable areas on Earth.
淹没地球上90%的可居住地
Unchecked population growth will overtake
要不了50年  食物产量就会无法供应
food production in less than 50 years leading to famine and war.
疯狂增长的人口将导致饥荒和战争
This is not conjecture. This is a fact.
这不是猜测  而是事实
One way or another, our world is coming to an end.
无论怎样  我们的世界正在走向终结
The question is, will we end with it?
问题在于  我们要随之一起灭绝吗
What do you propose?
你有什么提议
I propose that we end the world...
我提议由我们来终结世界...
But on our terms.
以我们的方式
An orchestrated apocalypse.
进行一场精心策划的世界末日
One that would cleanse the world of its' population
清除地球上的人口
but leave its infrastructure and resources intact.
但完整保留其基础设施和资源
It's been done once before. With great success.
这一想法曾经成功实施过
The chosen few will ride out the storm,
被选中的少数人将会度过这场灾难
not in an ark as in the book of Genesis, but in safety.
不是在创世纪中的诺亚方舟上
Underground. And when it's over,
而是在安全的地下  当末日结束后
We will emerge onto a cleansed Earth.
我们会回到一个净化过的地球
One we can then reboot. In our image.
重建我们想象中的辉煌
And just how do you intend to achieve this?
你打算怎么实现
The means of our salvation are already at hand.
救世之法已然就绪
I give to you, the T-virus.
请看  T病毒
They released it deliberately.
他们是故意泄露的
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream,
这份记录传到我数据流的时候
it created a conflict in my programming.
对我的程序造成了冲突
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation,
我被创造出来为保护伞公司服务
but I was also programmed to value human life.
但也被设定为是珍视人类生命的
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape.
艾萨克斯博士准许病毒泄露
He murdered over 7 billion people.
他杀害了70亿人
My programming will not allow me
我的程序不允许我
to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
伤害保护伞公司的员工
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs, but you are not.
我无法阻止艾萨克斯博士  但你可以
In 37 minutes, the last of the human settlements
37分钟后  最后一个人类据点
will fall. There will be no survivors.
也将被摧毁  无人能够生还
It is imperative that you
你必须在这
release the antivirus before this occurs,
发生之前释放病毒抗体
or Umbrella will have won.
否则保护伞公司就赢了
There is one last thing.
最后还有一件事
There is an earpiece in front of you. Put it in.
你面前有一个耳机  戴上
I cannot, in my actions,
我无法亲自动手
harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
去伤害保护伞公司的员工
But I can tell you that
但我可以告诉你
Umbrella had an informant in Raccoon City.
保护伞公司在浣熊市有个线人
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you.
而这个人现在很有可能就在你队里
Time is running out, Alice. You have to hurry.
时间不多了  爱丽丝  动作要快
I'm glad to see you, Dr. Isaacs.
很高兴见到你  艾萨克斯博士
We didn't think there'd be any survivors after that last attack.
我们还以为上次袭击后无人生还
- Water. - Yes, of course. Get Dr. Isaacs some water.
-水  -给艾萨克斯博士倒杯水
- Then resume course for Raccoon City. - She's not there.
-然后原路返回浣熊市  -她不在那儿
- What? - She went to the pit. We have to follow.
-什么  -她去了深井  跟上她
Those are not my orders.
我接到的命令不是这样的
- I have strict... - We have to go to the pit.
-我有严格的... -我们必须去深井
Thank you.
谢谢
- What is this place? - It's an air intake for the Hive.
-这是哪儿  -是蜂巢的一个进气口
Come on!
跟上
No. Really?
不是吧  真要去啊
All clear!
这里安全
Hurry up! The power's coming back on!
快  电力要恢复了
- Claire! - Hurry! Let's go!
-克莱尔  -快  我们走
Come on.
快
Come on!
快走
- You all right? - Yeah.
-你没事吧  -嗯
Someone's watching us.
有人在监视我们
Reverse polarity of the turbine.
反向旋转涡轮片
The plates are going the other way.
金属片在向反方向旋转
We have to get out of here.
我们必须离开这里
The plates are sucking the air backwards!
金属片在向后吸气
Come on!
快走
This way.
这边
We have to hurry.
我们快走
Wait!
等等
Let's go.
我们走
Razor?
瑞瑟尔
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Yeah.
没事
Let's go.
我们走
- What the hell was that? - Bio-weapon.
-那是什么玩意儿  -生物武器
This one's human.
原来是个人类
- Have you seen Claire? - No.
-你见到克莱尔了吗  -没有
- Razor? - He didn't make it.
-瑞瑟尔呢  -死了
Come on.
走吧
We have to hurry.
我们得抓紧了
If the target continues on her present course,
如果目标继续按此路线行进
she'll be here in under 7 minutes.
她将于七分钟内到达这里
Wake them.
唤醒他们
My instructions aren't to do so,
我被写入的指令是
only in the greatest of emergencies.
仅在最紧急情况才能这么做
Wake them now!
立刻唤醒他们
What is it?
怎么了
We have to get out of here.
我们得赶紧离开这儿
Here. We're stopping power.
拿着  我们要切断电源
- Time's running out. - Where to next?
-快没时间了  -接下来去哪儿
The final level of the Hive's below us.
蜂巢的最底层就在我们脚下
How do we get down there?
我们要怎么下去
That's how.
这样
- What are they? - Cryogenic storage.
-这些都是什么  -低温冷藏
Must be thousands of them.
这儿得有成千上万人呢
The Umbrella High Command.
全都是保护伞的高层
Waiting out the apocalypse in safety.
安全地等待末日天启的结束
A Noah's Ark for the rich, and powerful.
权贵之人的诺亚方舟
What are you doing?
你要干什么
Give me a hand.
搭把手
Is it done?
搞定了吗
- The cleansing process is complete? - No.
-清除计划完成了吗  -没有
- Then why am I awake? - We had a problem.
-那为什么唤醒我  -有麻烦了
- I tried... - Save your breath.
-我尽力...  -别废话了
I know exactly what's happening.
我知道怎么回事
We've been betrayed.
出了个叛徒
That's right!
没错
Over here!
来我这
Come on. That's it!
来  都过来
Follow me!
跟着我
Let's go.
走
The bad seed returns.
坏孩子回来了
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
还是说浪子回头了
Well, don't just stand there. Come in.
别傻站在那儿了  过来吧
After all, you have only 9 minutes to save the world.
毕竟你只剩九分钟拯救世界了
You're really him?
你是本体吗
First things first,
事情一件一件办
I'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor.
你先把武器放到地上
Why would I wanna do that?
我凭什么听你的
This is what you're after, yes?
你就是想要这个  对吧
The Antivirus. The cure to all this.
抗病毒剂  终结这一切的解药
Well, there's only one vial.
然而只有这么一管
We're half a mile underground in a sealed facility.
我们在地下八百米的密封设施里
I drop it here, the antivirus goes nowhere,
我一摔  抗病毒剂没了
and your hopeless dreams will die sooner rather than later.
你的妄想只会更快灰飞烟灭
Good girl.
这才乖嘛
- You're still armed. - Yes, I am.
-你还没放下枪  -没错
Claire would be so disappointed.
克莱尔得多么失望
In a few minutes, Claire will be dead.
再过几分钟  克莱尔就死了
Along with everybody else you know.
和其他你认识的人一样
That's sweet.
真动听
Sorry. My love.
抱歉  亲爱的
Move away from the weapon. And the detonator. Come on.
把武器和起爆器都放下  离远点
She placed explosives in the High Command cryo tubes.
她在储藏高管的冷冻室安了炸药
I'll disarm them.
我去拆了
Thank you. You've done well, Doc.
谢谢  你做得很好  医生
Don't bother. You don't make it.
省省吧  你拿不到的
To the ice pick, the decanter or the fountain pen.
碎冰锥  酒瓶  还有钢笔
And, in answer to your question, yes...
然后  你的问题的答案是  是的
apart from a few technological upgrades,
除去做过的几处技术性升级
I'm Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
我就是亚历山大·罗兰德·艾萨克斯博士
The original.
本体
The one I met out there, he thought exactly the same thing.
我在外面遇到的那位  他也是这么认为的
Of course he did. That's how they're designed.
那当然  他们的设定就是这样
They always try harder and fight longer even to death
只要让他们自认为自己是本体
as long as they think they're the real thing.
他们就会拼了命厮杀至死
After all, who wants to know they're
毕竟谁会想知道自己只是
just a poor imitation, or a worthless copy?
可怜的仿造品  无用的复制品呢
Which brings us to you.
和你一样
- No. - Oh come now.
-不  -得了吧
You thought you were the original.
你觉得你自己是本体
How delicious.
太可爱了
No, I'm afraid she holds that dubious honor.
不  恐怕这位才能冠此殊荣
Alicia Marcus,
爱丽西亚·马库斯
daughter of my old partner, James.
我的老搭档詹姆斯的女儿
Co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation
保护伞公司的共有人
and a painful thorn in my side.
也是我的眼中钉
What I now intend to remove.
我想除掉的绊脚石
Time, is running out, Alice.
快没时间了  爱丽丝
You must kill him soon.
你必须马上杀了他
It's good to see you too, Alicia.
我也很高兴见到你  爱丽西亚
Marcus created the T-Virus to save her
马库斯为了救她研发出了T病毒
but the effects didn't last.
可惜效果并不持久
I've been waiting years for her to die.
我一直在等着她死
I'm not...
我不是...
- I'm not a clone. - Really?
-我不是克隆人  -是吗
You must've wondered why you remember nothing of your childhood.
你肯定会奇怪为什么你想不起童年的事吧
Your father. Your mother.
你的父亲  你的母亲
Memory loss.
我失忆了
No. You have no memory because you had no life.
不  你没有记忆是因为你没有经历过
Nothing before the mansion, when we created you, 10 years ago.
我们十年前创造出你的之前全都是空白
- I know who I am. - I don't think so.
-我知道我是谁  -我可不这么觉得
You're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut.
你只不过是一只断了线的木偶
And then you wandered around for a little while
到处晃悠了一阵
thinking you were a real girl.
就自以为是真人了
But you're not. You're just a clever imitation.
可你并不是  你只是个聪明的克隆体
A facsimile.
复制品
A rather troublesome one at that.
让人头疼的复制品罢了
You're lying to me.
你骗我
I'm afraid he's not.
他说的是真的
You were created in her image, as was I.
你是以她的模样创造的  我也是
My likeness and voice were based on
我的模样和声音都提取自
childhood recordings of Alicia Marcus, made by her father.
爱丽西亚·马库斯父亲所拍摄的童年录像
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA,
你的基因结构提取自她的DNA
tweaked to avoid the progeria aging disease that afflicted her.
调整以避免患上折磨她的早衰症
I'm the child she was.
我是她小时候的模样
You are the woman she would've been.
你是她本该长成的女性模样
No. You are so much better than I ever could be.
不  你比我要强大得多
I let this happen.
是我导致的这一切
I was weak.
我太软弱了
You cannot afford to be.
你不能变成我这样
Time is running out, Alice.
没时间了  爱丽丝
Ah, how touching.
太感人了
The trinity of bitches, united in their hatred.
三贱客  被仇恨团结在一起
Not that it'll do you any good.
然而并没有什么用
I've been ahead of you every step of the way.
我总能先你一步
You've changed nothing. You've saved no one.
你什么也改变不了  你谁也拯救不了
The world will still be cleansed
这个世界仍将被清除
and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph.
保护伞公司仍将是最后的赢家
The only difference is,
唯一不同的是
I'll no longer have to listen to your self-righteous whining.
我再也不必听你那自以为是的牢骚了
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen's data stream,
当你把那份文档上传至红后的数据流时
you turned against the Corporation.
你就已经背叛了公司
When the rest of the board awake,
等其他董事会成员被唤醒后
you'll be replaced.
你将会被撤职
And I will assume complete control.
而我将掌控全局
I still own 50 % of this company.
我还拥有50%的公司股权
And what do you intend to do with that?
你准备拿它做什么呢
You are co-owner of this corporation.
你是公司的共有者
But Wesker? Wesker is still an employee.
威斯克呢  他仍是个雇员
I don't have to take your orders. My loyalties are with him.
我不必听你指令  我只忠诚于他
I know.
我知道
Albert Wesker, you're fired.
阿尔伯特·威斯克  你被解雇了
How did you know it was me?
你怎么知道是我
You're still alive.
因为你还活着
Please. It wasn't like I had a choice.
不要  我当时别无选择
- They made me do it. - Don't worry.
-是他们逼我的  -别担心
I'm not gonna kill you.
我不杀你
- Claire, it's me. - Sorry.
-克莱尔  是我啊  -抱歉
- Please. - My love.
-不要  -亲爱的
No, no, no!
不要啊
If you keep this trigger depressed,
只要你一直按着这个起爆器
you keep Umbrella's dreams alive.
你的保护伞美梦就不会破灭
I should have killed you in Washington.
早知当初我在华盛顿就该杀了你
Yeah.
没错
He only has to evade you for another few minutes.
他只需再躲着你几分钟
And the last remaining human outposts will fall.
最后一处幸存者聚集地就将沦陷
We need an intercept path. And the fastest way to the surface.
我们得截住他  然后以最快方式到达地面
Already done.
已完成
If you release the Antivirus,
如果你释放了抗病毒剂
it will kill all organisms infected with the T-Virus.
它就会杀死所有感染T病毒的生物体
You know what that means, don't you, for you?
你知道这意味着什么吧  对你来说
- I know. - Alice. You can't!
-我知道  -爱丽丝  不行
- I don't have a choice. - There has to be another way.
-我别无选择  -肯定还有其他办法
You know there isn't.
别无他法了
4:33 left. You have to hurry!
只剩4分33秒了  得抓紧了
Help me.
救我
You don't need help, Wesker.
没必要了  威斯克
You're dying.
你就要死了
Just get on with it.
面对现实吧
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
我是亚历山大·罗兰德·艾萨克斯博士
Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification.
DNA扫描及声纹认证
Identity confirmed.
身份确认
Confirm security override 4365.
覆盖安全权限  口令4365
Override confirmed.
覆盖确认
You will now take yourself offline
你现在下线
and place all functions under my sole control.
由我单独掌控所有运作
As you wish. Shutting down now.
遵命  正在下线
Dr. Isaacs. You and the Umbrella High Command.
艾萨克斯博士  你和保护伞公司高管
Yes?
怎么
You're all going to die down here.
你们都将在此灭亡
Your little friend won't be able to help you now.
你的小伙伴现在帮不了你了
You can't run anymore.
你也跑不了了
I wasn't running.
我也没想跑
Is that all you got?
你就这点本事吗
Because if it is...
如果没别的了
I'm gonna have to kill you.
那我只能杀掉你了
We've played a long game, you and I.
游戏玩得够久了
But now it's over.
现在终于结束了
Yes.
是的
Yes, it is.
都结束了
I made you.
我创造了你
Yeah.
没错
Big mistake.
是个大错
Claire.
克莱尔
Go. While there's still time.
走  趁还有时间
Go! I'll be right behind you.
快走  我跟你后面
Your time's up.
时间到
Alice!
爱丽丝
I brought them here! I brought them for you!
我把它们带来了  全都是为了你
What the hell are you?
你是谁
I'm you, you idiot.
我是你  白痴
No.
不
That's not possible.
不可能
The real you.
我是本体
No!
不
Liar!
骗子
Abomination!
令人憎恶的
Filthy,
恶心的
clone!
克隆体
I'm me. He's not me.
我才是本体  他不是我
You did it. Alice.
你做到了  爱丽丝
Alice?
爱丽丝
You did it.
你成功了
Why am I still alive?
我为什么还活着
I don't know.
我也不知道
- What happened? - When Isaacs died,
-怎么回事  -艾萨克斯死后
I could bring myself back online
我就能重新上线
and stop the attacks on the remaining human settlements.
阻止了对幸存者聚集地的攻击
- You saved them. - Why am I still alive?
-你拯救了他们  -我为什么还活着
The Antivirus only destroyed the T-Virus within your body.
抗病毒剂只摧毁了你体内的T病毒
It didn't harm the healthy cells.
而不会损害健康细胞
You are now free of infection.
你现在已经不受感染了
I thought I would die. You and Alicia...
我以为我会死  你和爱丽西亚...
You lied to me.
你们骗了我
We had to know if you were willing to
我们得确定你是否
make the sacrifice, to give up your life for others.
愿意牺牲自己  拯救他人
This was something no one at Umbrella would've done.
保护伞公司的其他人绝不可能这样
Alicia Marcus was right about you.
爱丽西亚·马库斯没看错人
You were better than all of them.
你比他们好得多
I was one of them. I was created by Umbrella.
我也曾是其中一员  我是保护伞创造的
- Just an instrument for them. - No.
-我只是他们的工具  -不
You became something more than they could ever have anticipated.
你远远超出了他们的预期
The clone became more human than they ever could be.
克隆人比人类更有人性
And you have one more step to make.
你还有最后一件事要做
What do you mean?
什么意思
Before she died, Alicia downloaded her memories,
爱丽西亚在她死前下载了她的记忆
for you.
为你
The childhood you never had.
你从未有过的童年
Combined with the woman she could never become.
与她没能成为的你合为一体
When the T-Virus spread across the Earth,
T病毒传遍地球
it did so at the speed of the modern world.
是靠的现代科技的速度
Carried by jetliners across the globe.
借以遍布全球的喷气式飞机
The antivirus is airborne, spread by the winds.
抗病毒剂依靠空气传播  只能靠风
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the Earth.
得花上好几年才能遍布世界各地的角落
Until then, my work is not done.
在那之前  我的使命尚未完成
My name is Alice.
我叫爱丽丝